A piece of eight.
8玫西班牙银币 ?
Nine of them, you say.
你说有9覆
Our new friend in Singapore was very specific, sir.
我们在新加坡的一个新朋友 说得很明确 勋茧
Nine pieces of eight.
9枚西班牙银币
What's the significance of that?
我想知道这其中的意义
Does it matter? Nothing can hold against the armada.
谁也抵挡不住我们的舰队
Not with the Flying Dutchman at the lead.
如果没有“鬼船” 作先锋的话
Nothing we know of.
没有谁能阻挡我们
Your friend mention where the Brethren Court are meeting?
你的朋友有没有说 “海盗大会”在哪儿开 ?
He was mum on that, sir.
他没说 勋划
Then he knows the value of information.
这么说他知道情报的价值
Better keep this between ourselves.
这件事不要让外人知道
We don't want anyone running off to Singapore, do we?
我们不想让任何人 跑到新加坡去 对吧 ?
Ah, Admiral.
将军
You summoned me, Lord Beckett.
贝克特勋贡 你找我 ?
Yes. Something for you there.
是的 有些东西要交给你
Your new station deserves an old friend.
你的新岗位需要一位老朋友
Not more requisition orders?
再没有申请令了吗
No, sir. Execution.
是的 长官 死刑
The Brethren know they face extinction.
海盗明白他们难逃厄运
All that remains is for them to decide where they make their final stand.
他们目前唯一能做的是 选择自己最后的为宿
No one said anything about cold.
没人说过这地方这生冷
I'm sure there must be a good reason for our suffering.
我想我们唱受的苦难 肯定是有原因的
Why don't that obay woman just bring Jack back
为什么那个会焉术的女人 不能拯救杰克
the same way she brought back Barbossa?
就像救回巴博萨那样
Because Barbossa was only dead.
因为巴博萨只是死了
Jack Sparrow is taken, in body and soul,
而杰克.斯派罗的肉体和灵魂
to a place not of death but punishment.
被送往了受难地
The worst fate a person can bring upon himself.
一个人所能得到的
Stretching on forever.
…永无正境
That's what awaits at Davy Jones’ Locker.
这就是戴维. 琼斯在内王殿 准备的东西
I knew there was a good reason.
我就知道是有原因的
Nothing here is set.
这里什么也没标
They can't be as accurate as modern charts.
不可能和现代海图一样猜准
But it leads to more places.
但它标出了更多的地方
"Over the edge.
“到边缘上
Over again."
再翻过去”
Do you care to interpret, Captain Barbossa?
能解释一下吗 巴博萨船长?
Ever a-gazed upon the green flash, Master Gibbs?
看到过绿光闪现吗 吉布斯先生 ?
l reckon I seen my fair share.
我算是见多识广的了
Happens on rare occasion.
但这种情景非常罕见
The last glimpse of sunset a green flash shoots up into the sky.
在最后一抹夕阳中 一道绿光射向空中
Some go their whole lives without ever seeing it,
有人穷其一生亦难得相见
some claim to have seen it who ain't, and some say...
有人说曾见过 其实并无此事 有人说…
It signals when a soul comes back to this world from the dead.
这象征着死人的灵魂 又回到了人间
Sorry.
对不起
Trust me, young Master Turner,
相信我 特纳先生
it's not getting to the land of the dead that's the problem.
问题不是怎么去死亡之地
It's getting back.
问题是如何回来
Bloody hell. There's nothing left.
天哪 什么都没剩下
Jones is a loose cannon, sir.
琼斯根本管不住自己 勋间
Fetch the chest.
把箱子拿来
And the governor?
那总督呢?
He's been asking questions about the heart.
他一直在问那颗心的事儿
Does he know?
他知道了吗 ?
Then perhaps his usefulness has run its course.
也许他已经没有利用价值了
Steady, men.
稳住 伙计们
Go. All of you.
走 都给我走
And take that infernal thing with you.
把那个该死的东西也拿走吧
I will not have it on my ship!
我的船上不要这东西 !
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that. Because I will.
哦 真可异 因为我要那样做
Because it seems to be the only way to ensure that this ship do
因为这是唯一的方法 确保这条般
as directed by the Company.
按东印度贸易公司 的指令行事
We need prisoners to interrogate,
我们需要审问一些犯人
which tends to work best when they're alive.
只有他们活着才有价值
The Dutchman sails as its captain commands.
“鬼船”只听命于 自己的船长
And its captain is to sail it as commanded.
但它的船长要服从我的指挥
I would have thought you learned that when I ordered you to kill your pet.
我让你杀掉完物的时候 还以为你懂了这个道理
This is no longer your world, Jones.
这里不再是你的地盘了 琼斯
The immaterial has become...
非物质的鬼怪已变得…
.. immaterial.
…无人关紧要
How long do we continue not talking?
你要多久才愿意和我说话 ?
Once we rescue Jack everything will be fine.
只要把杰克救出来 一切都会恢复如常
Then we rescue Jack.
那我们就去把杰克救出来
For what we want most...
得到最想得到的东西…
. there is a cost must be paid in the end.
…最终总得付出代价
Barbossa, ahead.
巴博萨 在前面!
Aye, we're good and lost now.
是的 我们现在迷路了
Lost?
迷路了?
For certain you have to be lost to find the places can't be found.
当然 只有迷路 才能到达找不到的地方
Elseways everyone would know where it was.
否则的话 所有人都知道 这地方在哪儿了
- We're gaining speed. - Aye.
我们在加速 是的
To stations!
回到岗位上去 !
All hands to stations!
所有水手回到岗位上去 !
Rudder full. Hard aport! Gather way.
左满舵 ! 加速
Nay! Belay that! Let her run straight and true!
不! 且慢! 让它照直前行 !
Blimey.
天哪
You've doomed us all.
你想把我们都再死
Don't be so unkind.
别这么不客气
You may not survive to pass this way again,
你也许不能活着回来
and these be the last friendly words you'll hear.
也许这是你能听到的 最后的真心话了
Tie her off.
搜住好
Hard to port!
左满舵
Hold on!
坚持住 !
Strike your colors, you blooming cockroaches.
降下船旗 你们这些该死的策蛋
Dead men tell no tales.
死人不会告密
My peanut.
我的花生
Haul the halyard. Slacken braces.
拉起升降索 松开操帆索
Aye, Captain. Slacken braces.
是 船长 松开操帆索
Step lively with a will.
我要底下把火生起来 !
Help.
救命
Man the yards, you filthy toads.
把人安排好 你这讨厌的家伙
Haul the sheets handsomely, boys. Scandalize and let's heave.
把帆聊索拉得漂亮些 减少三角帆
- Mr. Sparrow? - Aye, Captain.
斯派罗先生 ? 是 船长
What say you about the condition of this tack line?
你觉得这根系帆索还结实吗 ?
- It be proper to my eyes, sir. - Proper?
我看没问题 长官 没问题 ?
It is neither proper nor suitable, sir. It is not acceptable nor adequate.
不是没问题或有问题 先生 不是可接受的或恰当的
It is, in obvious fact, an abomination.
这简直是难以容忍的
Begging your pardon, sir, but perhaps if you gave a man another chance.
请求您的宽恕 长官 再给我一灾机会
Shall I?
我该给吗 ?
It's that sort of thinking got us into this mess.
让我们陷入到这种困境
We have lost speed and therefore time.
我们失去了速度 因此也就失去了时间
Precious time which cannot be recovered once lost.
宝贵的时间 将一去不复返
- Do you understand? - Aye, aye, Captain.
明白了吗? 是 船长
Do you now?
真的吗 ?
It will all have to be redone. All of it.
重新再做一遍
And let this serve as a lesson to the lot of you.
让你们都记住这教训
Doldrum, sir, has the entire crew on edge.
消沉的情绪 把船员都逼到了绝望的边缘
l have no sympathy for any of you feculent maggots
我不会同情你们任何一个和白病
and no more patience to pretend otherwise.
也没有耐心去装蒜
Gentlemen...
先生们
..l wash my hands of this weirdness.
我不会接受这种命运
No wind.
没有凤
Of course there's no bloody wind.
当然 一点凤都没有
My soul I do swear for a breeze.
我真心渴求一丝微风
A gust. A whisper. A tiny, miniature lick.
阵风 轻轻的 小小的 一点点
Yes, sir, know, but why would he do that?
是的 先生 我知道 但是为什么他要这么做?
Because he's a lummox.
因为他是个策蛋 对吗 ?
We shall have a magnificent garden party, and you're not invited.
我们要举办一个大聚会 不邀请你
Shoo.
河
Arock.
石头
Now we're being followed by rocks. Never had that before.
现在石头都在跟踪我们 以前从没有过这种事
A rope.
绳子
This truly is a godforsaken place.
这真是一块荒无人烟的地方
I don't see Jack. I don't see anyone.
我看不到杰克 看不到任何人
He's here.
他就在这里
Davy Jones never once gave up that what he took.
戴维. 琼斯不会放弃 他得到的东西
And does it matter?
这有父系吗?
We're trapped here by your doing, no different than Jack.
你的所作所为将我们困在此地 和赤克的命运没什么不同
..iS closer than you think.
比你们想象得更接近
Impossible.
不可能
Boat.
船
Slap me thrice and hand me to me mama. It's Jack.
真是撞见鬼了 是杰克
- It's the captain! - A sight for sore eyes.
是船长 ! 真开心
- Jack. - Mr. Gibbs.
吉布斯先生
- Aye, Captain. - [ thought so.
是 船长 我想也是
l expect you are able to account for your actions, then.
我希望你们能解释一下 你们此行的目的
Sir?
什么 ?
There has been a perpetual and virulent lack of discipline upon my vessel.
为什么我的船会如此的 混乱不堪 毫无章法 ?
- Why is that, sir? - Sir, you're...
为什么会这样 ? 船长 你…
You're in Davy Jones’ Locker, Captain.
你是在戴维. 琼斯的阎王殿里
I know that.
我知道
I know where I am. And don't think I don't.
我知道我在哪儿 别以为我不知道
Jack Sparrow.
杰克“. 斯派罗
Hector.
哦 赫克托
It's been too long, hasn't it?
好久不见了 对吧 ?
Aye. Isla de Muerta, remember? You shot me.
是的 死亡之岛 记得吗? 你朝我开枪
No, I didn't.
不 我没有
Tia Dalma, out and about, eh?
达尔玛 出来转转 ?
You add an agreeable sense of the macabre to any delirium.
你让藉神错乱 多了些令人恐怖的感觉
He thinks we're a hallucination.
他以为我们是幻觉
William, tell me something.
威廉 你告诉我
Have you come because you need my help
你到这里是要我帮忙
to save a certain distressing damsel... or rather damsel in distress?
择救一个使人痛苦的女人 还是郁救一个痛苦中的女人?
Then you wouldn't be here, would you? So you can't be here.
否则你不可能到这儿 对吗? 所以你不可能到这几
Q.E.D., you're not really here.
事实证明你没有真的到这几
This is real. We're here.
是真的 我们在这里
- "The Locker," you say? - Aye.
你是说阁王殿 ? 是的
We've come to rescue you.
我们来是为了救你
Have you now?
真的吗 ?
That's very kind of you.
那我还真得感谢你们了
But it would seem that as ! possess a ship and you don't,
不过我怎么觉得 我掌握着一条船，而你们没有
you're the ones in need of rescuing, and I'm not sure as I'm in the mood.
你们才是需要被拯救之人 不知道我有没有这份心情
Il see my ship.
我看到了我的船
Right there.
在那儿
I can't spot it.
看不见
Must be a tiny little thing hiding somewhere behind the Pear!
一定是太小了 被“黑珍珠号”给挡住了
Jack, Cutler Beckett has the heart of Davy Jones.
杰克 卡特勒 . 贝克特 得到了戴维: 琼斯的心
- He controls the Flying Dutchman. - He's taking over the seas.
他掌控着“鬼船” 他要控制大海
The song has already been sung. The Brethren Court is called.
歌声已经响起 海盗大会即将召集
Leave you alone and look what happens. Everything's gone to pot.
你们证我一个人采会儿 好好想想 这里乱套了
Aye. The world needs you back something fierce.
是的 这个世界需要你
And you need a crew.
而你需要船员
Why should I sail with any of you?
我为什么要跟你们一起航行 ?
Four of you have tried to kill me in the past. One succeeded.
过去你们之中有4个人想杀我 其中一个还得束了
She's not told you?
她没有告诉你们
You'll have loads to talk about while you're here.
既然你在这几 你应该说出来
As for you...
至于你
Now...
行了…
..don't tell me you didn't enjoy it at the time.
别黑我说 你当时不开心
Fair enough. All right, you're in.
说得对 好 你可以上船
Don't need you. You scare me.
不要你 你的样子吓人
Gibbs, you can come. Marty...
吉布斯 你可以来 马菇
Cotton. Cotton's parrot I'm a little iffy,
科顿 还有你的鹦扯
but at least I'll have someone to talk to.
至少有人下我说话了
Who are you?
你是谁?
Tai Huang. These are my men.
戴局 这些是我的人
Where do your allegiances lie?
你们效患谁 ?
With the highest bidder.
那要看谁开的价钱高
l have a ship.
我有船
That makes you the highest bidder.
那你自然就是我们的船长
Good man.
说得好
Weigh anchor, all hands. Prepare to make sail.
起错 准备启航 起锚
Which way you going, Jack?
你要去哪儿 杰克 ?
Trim that sail. Slack windward brace and sheet.
随风扬饥 松开迎风 操栅索和凯脚索
Haul the pennant line.
拉紧短索
- What are you doing?
你在干什么 ?
- No, what are you doing?
不 你在干什么 ?
- Captain gives orders on a ship. - The captain is giving orders.
只有船长才能下命令 船长正在发号施令
- My ship makes me captain. - They be my charts.
我的船当然我是船长 这是我的海图
That makes you chartman.
正好可以当“海图员”
Stow it, the both of you! That's an order! Understand?
你们两个都闭嘴 ! 这是命令 ! 懂吗 ?
Sorry. I just thought with the captain issue in doubt,
抱散 我只是想 既然船长人选未定
I'd throw in my name for consideration.
我毛遂自荐供大家考虐
Sorry.
抱攻
I'd vote for you.
我投你一标 是吗?
You left Jack to the kraken.
你把杰克丢给了海妖
He's rescued now. It's done with.
他现在获救了 一切都过去了
Will, ! had no choice.
威尔 我别无选择
You chose not to tell me.
你选择不告诉我
I couldn't.
我不能说
It wasn't your burden to bear.
这不僚你的事几
But I did bear it, didn't I?
可它和我有僚 对吗 ?
I just didn't know what it was.
我只是不知道为什么
I thought...
我以为…
You thought I loved him?
你以为我爱他
If you make your choices alone, how can I trust you?
如果你自作主张 我怎么信任你?
You can't.
你的确不能
Eerie.
可怕
That's downright macabre.
实在太可怕了
l wonder what would happen if you dropped a cannonball on one of them.
扔一个炸弹下去不知会怎么样
Be disrespectful it would.
这样太失礼了
They should be in the care of Davy Jones.
他们应该是戴维. 琼斯僚照的人
That was the duty him was charged with...
这是他的任务…
..by the goddess Calypso.
…是女神卡吕普索交给他的
To ferry those who die at sea to the other side.
把海中死难者运到另一个世界
And every ten years, him could come ashore...
每隔10年… …他会到岸上来…
..to be with she who love him.
…与他真正相爱的人团聚
But the man has become a monster.
但是这个人已经变成了魔鬼
So, he wasn't always... tentacle-y?
这么说 他不是什么时候都 张牙舞不地伸着触角 ?
No.
不
Him was a man...
他是个人…
Now his boat's coming.
现在有船开过来了
They're not a threat to us.
他们没有威胁到我们
Am I right?
对吗?
We are nothing but ghosts to them.
对他们来说我们只是鬼魂
It's best just let them be.
最好不要打扰他们
It's my father. We've made it back.
是我父亲 我们回来了
Father! Here, look here!
和爸1和多往这几看!
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
We're not back.
我们没有回来
Father!
和爸!
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
Are you dead?
你死了吗 ?
I think lam.
不 不 我想我已经死了
No, you can't be.
不 你不能死
There was this chest, you see.
有这样的一个箱子
It's odd.
很奇特
At the time it seemed so important.
有时候它显得很重要
Come aboard.
到船上来
And a heart.
还有一颗心
I learned that if you stab the heart, yours must take its place...
我听说如果你刺中它 你的心就会取代它的位置
..and you will sail the seas for eternity.
永远航行在大海中
The Dutchman must have a captain.
“鬼船”必须要有船长
Silly thing to die for.
为它去死很愚春
Someone, cast a line. Come back with us!
来人呀 扔给他一根缆绳 输我们一起走吧
A touch of destiny.
命运的…感触
Take the line.
接住缆绳
I'm so proud of you, Elizabeth.
我为你感到骄傲 伊丽莎和白
The line! Take the line!
各 缆绳 ! 抓住缆绳 !
- She must not leave the ship! - Father!
不能让她离开船 和爸!
Please come with us!
求你跟我们一起走 !
I won't leave you!
求你!别!我不让你走!
I'll give your love to your mother.
我会替你向妈妈问好的
- L won't let you go. - Elizabeth.
我不让你走! 伊丽莎和白
Is there a way?
有别的办法吗 ?
Him at peace.
愿他安息
No water.
没水了
Why is all but the rum gone?
怎么除了朗姆酒什么都没了 ?
Rum's gone, too.
朗姆酒也没了
If we cannot escape these doldrums before night,
天黑之前如果我们逃不出 亦道无风带
I fear we will sail on trackless seas...
我们就会漂泊在大海上
..doomed to roam the reach between worlds...
永远也到不了目的地
.. forever.
永远
And no water forever looks to be arriving a mite too soon.
没有水 永远看上去 来得稍微旱了点几
Why doesn't he do something?
他为什么不想想办法 ?
There's no sense to it.
搞不懂这东西
The green flash happens at sunset...
绿光出现在日落
.-not sunrise.
不是在日出
Over the edge.
“到边缘上”
That's driving me over the blooming edge.
它已经把我 逼到该死的边缘了
Sunrises don't set.
旭日不会落
That's just maddeningly unhelpful.
这简直是废话
Why are these things never clear?
有话干嘛不直说?
- Clear as mud, Jackie. - What?
莫名其妙 杰克 什么 ?
- Stab the heart. - Don't stab the heart.
扎那颗心 别扎
- Come again? - The Dutchman must have a captain.
再说一遍 ? “鬼船”必须要有船长
That's even more than less than unhelpful.
这比没用更没用
Sail the seas for eternity.
永远漂泊在大海上
I love the sea.
我喜欢大海
What about port?
港口呢?
I prefer rum. Rum's good.
我喜欢朗姆酒 朗姆酒好喝
Making port.
停靠港口
Where we can get rum and salty wenches...
就可以弄到 妆姆酒和女人…
..once every ten years.
隔10年一均
- What did he say? - Once every ten years.
他说什么 ? 每隔10年一次
Ten years is a long time, mate.
10年太长了 饮计
Even longer given the deficit of rum.
没有朗姆酒的日子更长
But eternity is longer still.
但都比不上永远
And how will you be spending it?
你打算怎么消磨时间 ?
Dead... or not?
死?还是不死?
The immortal Captain Sparrow.
不朽的斯派罗船长
like that.
哦 这个我喜欢
Come sunset, it won't matter.
日落并不重要
Not sunset.
不是日落
Sundown.
太阳落下
And rise. Up.
升起来 向上
What's that?
那是什么 ?
What is that? I don't know. What do you think?
不知道 你说呢 ?
- Where? - There.
在哪儿 ? 在那儿
What is it?
什么东西?
He's rocking the ship.
他在援船
We're rocking the ship.
我们在摇船
Aye.
是的
He's onto it.
他明白了
He's rocking the ship.
他在援船
We'll tie each other to the mast, upside down,
我们头冲下绑在桥杆上
so when the boat flips, we'll be the right way up.
船翻了的时候 我们正好头冲上
Time it with the swell.
按着节奏
Loose the cannons, you lazy bilge rats.
把大炮解开 你们这群 懒情的仓底老鼠
Unstow the cargo.
把捆绑货物的绳子松开
Now up...
现在向上
..is down.
就是向下
This was your idea.
都是你出的主意
Blessed sweet Westerns!
上帝保佑可爱的西风带 !
We're back!
我们回来了 !
It's the sunrise.
现在是日出
Parley?
谈判 ?
We need our pistols! Get untied. Hurry!
我们也得拿枪 ! 把绳子解开 快 !
All right, then!
别笑了 !
The Brethren Court is gathering at Shipwreck Cove.
海盗大会将在沉船湾举行
And Jack, you and I are going, and there will be no arguing that point.
杰克 你和我去参加 这一点不会有异议
lis arguing the point.
我有异议
If there's pirates gathering, I'm pointing my ship the other way.
如果要开什么海盗大会 我可不去
The pirates are gathering to fight Beckett, and you're a pirate.
海盗聚会是为了对抗贝克特 你也是海盗
Fight or not, you're not running, Jack.
去还是不去 友正你不能走 杰克
If we don't stand together, they'll hunt us down
我们如果不团结 他们会一个一个地干掉我们
till there will be none left but you.
到时候就剩下你自己了
Quite like the sound of that.
我喜欢这个说法
Captain Jack Sparrow...
杰克“. 斯派罗
. the last pirate.
最后的海盗
Aye. And you'll be fighting Jones alone.
是的 你将和琼斯独自作战
How does that figure into your plan?
你考谍过吗 ?
But I will not be going back to the Locker, mate.
但我不会再回韶王磺 伙计
Count on that.
相信我
Wet powder.
火药进水了
Wait!
等等!
We can still use them as clubs!
他们至少可以当棍子用
Sorry. Effective, though.
抱火 还插有效的
There's a freshwater spring on this island.
这个岛点上有淡水
We resupply there and get back to shooting each other later.
我们先到那儿去补充淡水 然后再自相残杀
You lead the shore party. I'll stay with my ship.
你带队上涯 我和船采在一起
I'll not be leaving my ship in your command.
我不会将船留给你来指挥
Why don't you both go ashore and leave the ship in my command?
你们俩都上涯 船由我来照看怎么样
Temporarily.
临时的
Criminy.
小 心船
Odds bodkins!
天哪 上帝!!
Careful! Careful!
小 心 了 小 心 了
You stupid fish!
你这条愚的鱼 !
- Actually, it's a cephalopod. - Serves you right.
这上其实是条章鱼 活该
bet people would pay a shilling to see this.
我敢打赌大家 背交一先令来看这个
And a shilling for a sketch of them sitting atop!
再加一先令可以给你画一张 章鱼坐在上面的速罕
Pintel and Ragetti, kraken slayers.
平特尔和拉杰蒂 海怪杀手
Think you can outrun the world?
想如何能跑出这个世界?
The problem with being the last of anything...
知道吗 问题是 不管成为最后的什么…
..by and by there be none left at all.
…要不了多久 都会灰飞烟灭
Sometimes things come back, mate.
有时候事物还会死而复生
We're living proof, you and me.
我们就是活生生的例证
Aye, but that's a gamble of long odds, ain't it?
但这极为偶然 不是吗 ?
There's never a guarantee of coming back.
死而复生的保证根本没有
But passing on, that's dead certain.
而死是必然的
Summoning the Brethren Court, then, is it?
那么召集海盗大会 是吗?
It's our only hope, lad.
这是我们唯一的希望
That's a sad commentary in and of itself.
这名话本身就是 一种可悲的表述
The world used to be a bigger place.
世界曾经是一个很大的地方
The world is still the same.
世界还是那个世界
There's just less in it.
只是其中的真麟不多了
Poisoned. Fouled by the body.
有毒 被尸体污染了
l know him.
我认识他
He was in Singapore!
他当时在新加坡 !
Captain!
船长 !
We got company!
我们有伴儿啦 !
He's the captain.
他是船长
Sao Feng, you showing up here 'tis truly a remarkable coincidence.
趾凤…你在这里出现 这是出人意料的巧合呀
Jack Sparrow.
杰克“. 斯派罗
You pay me great insult once.
你给过我一炊极大的侮厚
That doesn't sound like me.
听起来好像不是我
Shall we just call it square, then?
这样是不是扯平了?
Release her.
放开她
She's not part of the bargain.
她和这笔交易没父系
And what bargain be that?
这是什么样的一笔交易 ?
You heard Captain Turner.
听到特纳船长说的了吗
- Release her! - Captain Turner?
放了她 ! 特纳船长?
The perfidious rotter led a mutiny against us!
背信弃义的小人 竞节把我们出卖了!
I need the Pear! to free my father.
我需要“黑珍珠”救我父亲
That's the only reason I came on this voyage.
这是我此葡航海的唯一目的
Why didn't you tell me you were planning this?
你为什么不告诉我你的计划 ?
He needs the Peart.
他想要“黑珍珠号”
Captain Turner needs the Pearl.
特纳船长想要“黑珍珠号”
And you felt guilty.
你感到做贼心庶
And you and your Brethren Court.
你和你的海盗大会
Did no one come to save me just because they missed me?
有谁是因为想我才去救我的?
I'm standing over with them.
我去和他们站到一块几
..but there is an old friend who wants to see you first.
不过有个 老朋友想见你
I'm not certain I can survive any more visits from old friends.
再见几个老朋友 我不知道还能不能活下去
Here is your chance to find out.
不芒碰碰运气
Curious.
有意思
Your friends appear to be quite desperate, Jack.
你的朋友似乎很绝望 杰克
Perhaps they no longer believe a gathering of squabbling pirates
他们或许不再相信 一群岛合之众
can defeat the Flying Dutchman.
能打败“撮船”
And so despair leads to betrayal.
绝望导致背叛
But you and I are no strangers to betrayal, are we?
你我对背叛都不陌生吧 ?
It's not here, Jack.
它不在这几 杰克
- What isn't? - The heart of Davy Jones.
什么?什么不在这几? 戴维. 琼斯的心
It's safely aboard the Dutchman
在“鬼船”上
and so unavailable for use as leverage
所以想拿它来做筹码
to satisfy your debt to the good captain.
去偿还你的债务是没用的
By my reckoning, that account has been settled.
在我看来 那笔账已经一笔匀销了
By your death?
用你的死?
And yet here you are.
可你又复活了
Close your eyes, pretend it's all a bad dream. That's how I get by.
闭上你的眼睛 就当这一切 是场悉梦 这就是我的办法
And if Davy Jones were to learn of your survival?
假如戴维. 琼斯知道 你死而复生 那会怎么料 ?
My men are crew enough.
我的人都是非常好的水手
Company ship, Company crew.
公司的船用公司的水手
You agreed. The Black Pear! was to be mine.
你答应过 “黑珍珠号”愉我
And so it was.
以前是这样
Perhaps you'll consider an alternative arrangement,
或许你会考虑另一个选择
one which requires absolutely nothing from you...
不需要你做出任何牺糙
..but information.
只要你延露一些情报
Regarding the Brethren Court, no doubt,
估于海盗大会的
in exchange for fair compensation.
当然会有合理的补偿
Square my debt with Jones...
偿还我从琼斯的债…
..and guarantee my freedom.
…确保我的自由?
Of course.
当然
It's just good business.
这是一笔好买卖
Were I in a divulgatory mood...
让我告诉你什么呢?
Where are they meeting?
他们在哪儿聚会 ?
Who are the pirate lords?
参加会议的是谁?
What is the purpose of the nine pieces of eight?
9块西班牙银币 是什么意思 ?
Beckett agreed...
贝克特同意
..the Black Pearl was to be mine.
“黑珍珠号”愉我
Lord Beckett won't give up the only ship that can outrun the Dutchman.
他不会放弃这条唯一能
Shame they're not bound to honor the code of the Brethren, isn't it?
可惜 他们是不会尊重 海盗法则的
Because honor is a hard thing to come by nowadays.
因为现今 很难再看到守信的人
There is no honor to remaining with the losing side.
对失败者没有信誉可讲
Leaving it for the winning side, that's just good business.
还是留着给胜利者吧 这只是一宗好买卖
The losing side, you say?
你是说 失败者 ?
They have the Dutchman... now the Pear!
他们有“鬼船” 现在又有了“黑珍珠号”
And what do the Brethren have?
海盗有什么 ?
We have... Calypso.
我们有卡吕善索女神
Calypso.
卡吕普索女神
An old legend.
一个吉老的传说
No.
不
The goddess herself, bound in human form.
是真的女神 被因禁成人形的女神
Imagine all the powers of the seas
想象一下 用大海的
brought to bear against our enemy. l intend to release her.
全部力量抗击我们的数人 我打算放了她
For that I need the Brethren Court.
但为此我需要召开海盗大会
All the Court.
所有海盗
You can keep Barbossa,
你可以把巴博萨留下
the belligerent homunculus and his friend with the wooden eye.
那个好战的矮人和他的朋友 那个装着假眼的
And Turner. Especially Turner.
还有特纳 尤其是特纳
The rest go with me aboard the Peart. I'll lead you to Shipwreck Cove,
剩下的人跟我上“黑珍珠号” 我带你去沉船湾
where I will hand you the pirates and you will not hand me to Jones.
在那儿我把你要的人给你 前提是不能把我交给琼斯
Bloody fair deal, don't you think?
很合算的买卖 怎么样 ?
And what becomes of Miss Swann?
斯旺小姐呢 ?
What interest is she to you?
你对她有什么兴趣吗 ?
What are you proposing, Captain?
你有什么建议 船长?
What be accepted, Captain?
你要什么条件 船长?
- The girl. - What?
那个女孩 什么 ?
Jack, I've just recalled...
杰克 我刚想到
I've got this wonderful compass,
我得到了一个奇妙的指南针
which points to whatever I want.
它能给我指出我想要的东西
So for what do I need you?
所以我还要你做什么呢?
Elizabeth is not part of any bargain.
不能拿伊丽落和白做交易
Out of the question.
没问题
It was not a question.
这不是个问题
Points to the thing you want most. That is not the Brethren Court, is it?
把你最想要的东西指出来 不是海盗大会 对吧 ?
Then what is, Jack?
那又是什么呢 杰克 ?
Me...
是我
..dead.
我的命
Done.
成交
What? Not done.
什么 ? 不行
You got us into this mess. If this frees us, done!
是你使我们落到这个地步 如果能自由 那就成交
Damn.
该死
Although, if I kill you,
尽管如此 如果杀了你
then I can use the compass to find Shipwreck Cove, is it...
我可以用指南针 自己去
..on my own.
寻找沉船湾
Cut out the middleman, as it were.
抛开中间人
Elizabeth, they are pirates.
伊丽莎白 他们是海盗
l have had more than enough experience dealing with pirates!
我有足够的经验对付海盗 !
Then we have an accord.
那我们就说定了?
With me killed, you'd arrive at the Cove,
我是死了 但你到了沉船湾
find it a stronghold nigh impregnable...
却发现那是个 攻不可破的要塞…
..able to withstand blockade for years, and then you'd be wishing,
…能支撑数年之久
"Oh, if only there was someone l had not killed inside
那时你就会想“当初不杀他 就好了 留着他当内应
to ensure that the pirates then come outside."
确保到时把海盗引到外面”
And you can accomplish all this?
你能做到这些吗 ?
You may kill me, but you may never insult me.
你可以杀我 但不可以侮辱我
Who am I?
我是谁啊?
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
我是杰克“斯派罗船长
Done!
成交了!
You're mad.
你鸳了
Thank goodness. If l wasn't, this would probably never work.
感谢上帝 幸亏我疯了 不然肯定没戏
And that was without even a single drop of rum.
我连一滴朗姆酒都没酒 就跑出来了
Send this pestilent, traitorous, cow-hearted codpiece to the brig.
把这个讨厌胆小不患的混蛋 估到禁闭室去
Which ship do we follow?
我们跟踪哪条船 ?
Signal the Dutchman to track down Sao Feng. We follow the Peart.
我们跟随“黑珍珠”
How soon can we have the ship ready to pursue?
还有多久和能出发 ?
Do you think he plans it all out
你觉得他是计划好的
Sorry.
勋站
By this time tomorrow, we will arrive at Shipwreck Cove
明天这时候 我们将到达 沉船湾
and you will be free.
到时候你就自由了
Calypso.
卡吕普索
Excuse me?
你说什么 ?
Not a name you fancy, I imagine,
我想在诸多称谓当中
out of the many that you have...
这不是你喜欢的名字…
..but it is what we call you.
…可这是我们对你的称呼
We being who?
我们指的是谁?
You confirm it.
你使我确信
Confirm what?
确信什么 ?
You've told me nothing.
你什么都没有告诉我
The Brethren Court, not I.
海盗大会 不是我
The first Brethren Court,
第一届海盗大会
whose decision I would have opposed.
我本来可以反对他们的决定
They bound you to human form,
他们把你囚禁成人形
so the rule of the seas would belong to Man, and not...
以便让大海的统治汶属于 男人 而不再属于…-
Me.
我
But one such as you should never be anything less than what you are.
但是像你这样不凡的人 绝对不该甘于平凡
Pretty speech from a captor,
红押者的花言巧语
but words whispered through prison bars lose their charm.
但牢笼的铁窗传出来的 声音会失去鬼力
Can I be blamed for my efforts?
我要为自己的努力 而备受指责吗 ?
All men are drawn to the sea, perilous though it may be.
所有男人都到海上去了 虽然那里很危险
And some men offer desire as justification for their crimes.
有的男人把欲望当成 犯罪的理由
l offer simply my desire.
我这里只有和谷望
And in return?
拿什么作交换 ?
I would have your gifts...
我要你的馈赠
.-Should you choose to give them.
如果你选择给的话
And if l should choose... not?
如果我选择不呢 ?
.-your fury.
…无礼了
Sao Feng.
叶风?
Please.
快
With all nine pieces of eight...
拿到所有的9枚西班牙银币…
..you will be free.
…你就自由了
Take it!
拿着吧 !
You are captain now.
你现在是船长了
Me?
我?
Go in my place...
代表我…
..to Shipwreck Cove.
…去沉船湾
Captain, the ship is taken.
船长 ! 船被占领了 我们无法…
Forgive me, Calypso.
原谅我…卡吕普索女神
What did he tell you?
他跟你说了些什么 ?
He made me captain.
他让我当船长
You are not my captain.
你不是我的船长
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
James.
磨姆斯 麻姆斯
Thank God you're alive.
谢天谢地 你还活着
Your father will be overjoyed to know you're safe.
你父亲知道你还活着 会高兴死的
My father's dead.
我父亲已经死了
No, that can't be true. He returned to England.
不 这不可能 他回英国了
Did Lord Beckett tell you that?
贝克特勋吉告诉你的?
Who among you do you name as captain?
你们中间谁是船长?
Captain. Her.
船长 她
- Captain. - Tow the ship.
船长? 把船拖走
Put the prisoners in the brig.
把犯人估起来
The captain shall have my quarters.
船长住我的船舱
Thank you, sir.
谢谢 先生
But I prefer to remain with my crew.
但我宁愿和我的船员们在一起
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
I swear...
我发炙
- .... did not know. - Know what?
我不知道 知道什么 ?
Which side you chose.
选择站在哪一边 ?
Well, now you do.
现在你知道了
Here.
这里
Bootstrap?
布斯找珀 ?
Bootstrap.
布斯搜珀
Bill Turner?
比尔. 特纳 ?
You know my name.
你知道我的名字
Yes, I know your son.
是的 我认识你的儿子
Will Turner.
威尔. 特纳
William.
威廉
He made it. He's alive.
他成功了 他还活着
And now he sends you to tell me that he's coming to get me.
现在他派你来告诉我 他正准备来救我
God's wounds. He's on his way.
上帝 他准备来救我
And he wants to help you.
他想救你出去
He can't help me. He won't come.
他帮不了我 他不会来
But you're his father.
但你是他父亲
I know you.
我知道你
He spoke of you.
他提起过你
He can't save me. He can't come because of you.
他救不了我 他不能来是因为你
Me?
我?
You're Elizabeth.
你是伊丽莎白
Yes, I'm Elizabeth.
是的 我是伊丽落和白
If Jones be slain. He who slays him, must take his place.
如果琼斯被杀 杀死他的人将取代他的位置
Captain. Forever.
当船长…永远
The Dutchman must always have a captain.
“鬼船”必须要有船长
And if he saves me...
如果他救我…
..he loses you.
…就会失去你
I see.
我明白了
He won't pick me.
他不会选择我
I wouldn't pick me.
我不会选择我
Tell him not to come.
告诉他别来
Tell him to stay away.
告诉他远远地离开这几
Tell him it's too late.
告诉他已经太迟了
I'm already a part of the ship...
我已经成了这条船的一部分…
Bootstrap.
布斯搜珀
You know my name.
你知道我的名字
Yes, I know your son.
是的 我认识你的儿子
William.
威廉
He's coming for me.
他来找我了
Wait and see.
等着瞧吧
Sir.
勋站
A breadcrumb trail.
有浮己
And we're meant to follow.
我们应该沿着这条路走
A betrayer among them?
他们里面有叛徒吗?
Or a trap?
或者是一个骗局
A gambit by a skilled opponent.
狼狂的对手布置的棋局
Adjust course, Lieutenant.
调整航线 上尉
Sir?
勋贡 ?
We can only hope to reach our destination
只能希望 在他们的尸体用完之前
before they run out of bodies.
我们可以到达目的地
You escaped the brig even quicker than I expected.
你从牢房中逃出来的速度 比我想象的要快
William...
威廉…
..do you notice anything?
…你发现什么了吗?
Rather...
或者说…
..do you notice something that is not there to be noticed?
…你有没有发现一些 不该被发现的东西 ?
- You haven't raised an alarm. - Odd, isn't it?
你没有惊动别人 很奇怪 是吧?
Not as odd as this.
不如这个奇怪
Come up with this all by your lonesome, did you?
是你一个人想出来的?
I said to myself, "Think like Jack."
我对自己说“像杰克那样 思考问题”
This is what you've arrived at?
这就是你思考的结果 ?
Lead Beckett to Shipwreck Cove so as to gain his trust?
把贝克特引到沉船湾 换取他对你的信任…
Accomplish your own ends? It's like you don't know me at all.
…达到你的目的? 看来你根本就不了解我
And how does your dearly beloved feel about this plan?
你心爱的人会对这个计划 作何感想?
You've not seen fit to trust her with it.
你还是信不过她
I'm losing her.
我正在失去她 杰克
Every step I make for my father is a step away from Elizabeth.
离伊丽莎白就越远
If you choose to lock your heart away, you'll lose her for certain.
如果你选择自我封闭 那你肯定会失去她
If l might lend a machete to your intellectual thicket...
你不如转变思维…
Change the facts.
改变事实
Let someone else dispatch Jones.
让别人去杀琼斯
Who?
谁?
You?
你吗?
Death has a curious way of reshuffling one's priorities.
死亡有个奇怪的方式 能改变人的优先权
I slip aboard the Dutchman, find the heart, stab the beating thing,
找到并且刺中琼斯的心
your father goes free from his debt,
你父亲就可以获得解脱
you're free to be with your charming murderess.
你仍然可以和迷人的 女杀手在一起
You're willing to cut out your heart, bind yourself to the Dutchman...
你愿意把自己的心控出来 把自己与“鬼船”捆绑在一起
- .. forever. - No, mate.
直到永远? 不 伙计
I'm free forever.
我永远是自由的
Free to sail the seas beyond the edges of the map. Free from death itself.
在大海中自由航行 摆脱了死亡的威胁
You have to do the job, though.
可你得做那种工作 杰克
You have to ferry souls to the next world.
把灵魂运送到另一个世界中去
Or end up just like Jones.
或像琼斯一样死去
I don't have the face for tentacles.
我的脸可没地方长触角
But immortal has to count for something.
不过能够永生还是值得的 你说呢?
What's this for?
这是干什么用的?
Think like me. It'll come to you.
像我一样考虑问题 你就会明白
My regards to Davy Jones.
代我向戴维. 琼斯问好
l hate him.
我恨他
Come with me.
跟我来
Quickly.
快点
What are you doing?
你在做什么 ?
Choosing a side.
选择站在哪一碗
Do not go to Shipwreck Cove. Beckett knows of the meeting of the brethren.
不要去沉船湾 贝克特知道海盗要在那儿开会
I fear there may be a traitor among them.
我想他们中间有上叛徒
It's too late to earn my forgiveness.
现在要我原谅你太迟了
l had nothing to do with your father's death.
我和你父亲的死无从
But that doesn't absolve me of my other sins.
但这并不能 免除我的其它界草
Come with us.
趴我们一起走
James, come with me.
磨姆斯 跟我走
Who goes there?
谁在那儿 ?
Go. I will follow.
走 我会跟上的
You're lying.
你在撒谎
Our destinies have been entwined...
我们的命运纠鲁在一起 伊丽莎白…
..but never joined.
…但总是无法结合
Go, now.
快走
Back to your station, sailor.
回到你的岗位上去 水手
No one leaves the ship.
没有人可以离开这条船
Stand down.
退下
That's an order.
这是命令
Part of the crew, part of the ship.
水手中的一员 与船不可分害
Steady.
别紧张 伙计
All hands, prisoner escape!
有犯人逃跑了1!
- Belay that! - James!
住嘴 ! 摩姆斯 !
James! No! No!
磨姆斯1不1!
- The admiral's dead. - Admiral's dead?
将军死了 将军死了 ?
- To the captain's command! - Aye!
去船长室 ! 是 !
Back to the ship.
回到船上去
James Norrington. Do you fear death?
磨姆斯. 诺林上顿 你怕死吗 ?
I take that as a "no."
看来你不怕死
Nice sword.
很好的一把剑
The Dutchman...
“锡船”…
.iS under my command.
…由我来指挥
For now.
暂时
Look alive and keep a weather eye.
小心谨慎 保持丈惕
Not for naught it's called Shipwreck Island.
这地方叫沉船岛 再合适不过了
Where lies Shipwreck Cove and the Town of Shipwreck.
既有沉船湾 又有沉船镇
You heard him. Step lively.
都听到了吗 快点干活
For all that pirates are clever called, we are an unimaginative lot
都说海盗绝顶聪明 可一到起名字的时候
when it comes to naming things.
就都没有了想象力 是的
l once sailed with a geezer, lost both of his arms, part of his eye.
一赤我和一个老头出海 他没了有骆膊 只剩下一只服
What'd you call him?
他叫什么 ?
Larry.
拉里
I do not renege on a bargain once struck.
我做买卖决不食言
We agreed on ends only. The means are mine to decide.
不过我们只谈结果 过程由我来定
Caution, Barbossa.
小心点儿 巴博萨
Do not forget it was by my power you return from the dead.
别总了你的死而复生 是由于我的力量
Or what it mean if you fail me.
或者说失信于我意味着什么
Don't you forget why you had to bring me back.
你也别忘了 为什么你要让我死而复生
Why I could not leave Jack to his well-deserved fate.
为什么我不能丢下杰克不管
It took nine pirate lords to bind you, Calypso.
要用9个海盗首领 才能约束你 卡吕普索
And it'll take no less than nine to set you free.
而释放你恰恰也需要9个
Masters Pintel, Ragetti.
平特尔和拉杰蒂先生
Take this fish wife to the brig.
把这个渔蓝估起来
Right this way, Mrs. Fish.
这边走 鱼太太
I cannot be summoned like some mongrel pup.
我不可以像狗如种一样 被吃喝来吹喝去
Apparently, you can.
你当然可以
I believe you know each other.
我想你们相互认识
Come to join my crew again, Master Turner.
又加入我们的船员队伍了 特纳先生 ?
Not yours. His.
不是你的 是他的
Jack Sparrow sends his regards.
杰克“斯派罗代问你好
Sparrow?
斯派罗 ?
You didn't tell him.
你没告诉他 ?
We rescued Jack from the locker along with the Black Peart.
我们从阁王殿里救出了杰克 还找国了“黑珍珠号”
What else have you not told me?
你还有什么没告诉我?
There's an issue...
有一件更坏手的事
I believe you're familiar with a person called Calypso.
我想你一定认识一个叫 卡吕普索的人
Not a person.
那不是人
A heathen god. One who delights in cursing men with their wildest dreams
是一个异教神 喜欢用最疯狂的梦想折麻男人
and then revealing them to be hollow and naught but ash.
然后向他们揭示 这一切都是虚无肚渺的
The world is well rid of her.
这个世界最好摆脱掉她
Not quite so well, actually.
其实不那么好摆脱
The Brethren Court intends to release her.
海盗大会想灵放她
No! They cannot!
不 ! 他们不能 !
The first court promised to imprison her forever.
第一玫海盗大会 同意将她永远囚禁
- That was our agreement. - Your agreement?
这是我们的协定 你的协定 ?
l showed them how to bind her.
我告诉过他们如何因禁她
She could not be trusted. She gave me no choice.
她是不可信任的 她让我别无选择
We must act before they release her.
在她被放出来之前 我们必须采取行动
You loved her.
你爱好
She's the one.
她是你唯一的爱
And then you betrayed her.
之后你背叛了她
She betrayed me.
她背叛了我
And after which betrayal did you cut out your heart, I wonder.
我想知道你是在哪欢背叛 之后把心搁了出来
Do not test me.
不要来车我
I hadn't finished that.
我还没有说完
You will free my father.
你得放了我父亲
And you will guarantee Elizabeth's safety, along with my own.
你得保证伊丽落和白的安全 还有我的
Your terms are steep, Mr. Turner.
你的条件不合理 特纳先生
We will expect fair value in return.
我们要的是公平的交易
There is only one price I will accept.
我只接受一个条件
Calypso murdered.
杀了卡吕普索
Calypso's aboard the Black Pearl.
卡吕善索在“黑珍珠”上
Jack has sailed the Black Pear! to Shipwreck Cove.
杰克驾驶着“黑珍珠” 去了沉船湾
And with you no longer aboard her...
既然你已经不在那条船上了
.. how do you propose to lead us there?
如何能带着我们去那儿 ?
What is it you want most?
你到底最想要什么 ?
Look at them all.
看看他们
There's not been a gathering like this in our lifetime.
我们一磋子都没有这样 聚在一起过
And I owe them all money.
我欠了他们所有人的钱
As he who issued summons...
作为大会召集人
... convene this, the fourth Brethren Court.
我召集这次 第4届海盗大会
To confirm your lordship and right to be heard,
为了确认你们的首领地位 以及发号施令的权力
present now your pieces of eight, my fellow captains.
请出示你们的西班牙银币 我的船长们
Those aren't pieces of eight. They're just pieces of junk.
那些不是西班牙银币 那些都是破烂
The original plan was to use nine pieces of eight to bind Calypso,
原计划是用9块西班牙银币 因某住卡吕普索
but when the first court met, the brethren were to a one skint broke.
但第一灵大会召开时 大家都是一文不名的穷光蛋
- So change the name. - What?
那就把名字改掉
To "nine pieces of what we happen to have in our pockets at the time"?
改成“9个碰巧能从 帘里掏出来的东西”?
Oh, yes. That sounds very pirate-y.
对 这听起来更像海盗
Master Ragetti, if you will.
拉杰蒂先生 你能不能…
I kept it safe for you, just like you said when you gave it to me.
按你要求的 我一直在妥善保管着
Aye, you have. But now I need it back.
是的 很好 不过我现在要拿回来了
Sparrow?
斯派罗
Might I point out that we are still short one pirate lord
需要指出的是 我们还缺一位海盗首领
and I'm as content as a cucumber to wait until Sao Feng joins us.
我一直在等着啸风的到来
Sao Feng is dead.
趾凤死了
He fell to the Flying Dutchman.
他死在“和鬼船”的炮火之下
The plagued ship.
这条该死的船
He made you captain? They're giving the bloody title away.
他证你当船长了? 他们把头衔给别人了
Listen. Listen to me.
听着 听我说
Our location has been betrayed.
我们这个地方被人出卖了
Jones is under the command of Lord Beckett. They're on their way.
琼斯现在听命于贝克特勋凋 他们现在正往这里赶
Who is this betrayer?
谁是叛徒?了
Not likely anyone among us.
不一定是我们中间的人
- Where's Will? - Not among us.
威尔在哪儿 ? 他不在我们中间
And it matters not how they found us.
估键不是他们如何发现的我们
The question is, "What will we do now that they have?"
问题是 我们现在该怎么办?
We fight.
我们血战到底
Shipwreck Cove is a fortress.
沉船湾是一座要塞
A well-supplied fortress.
给养充足的堡侄
There is no need to fight if they cannot get to us.
他们如果接近不了我们 就没必要战斗
There be a third course.
我们还有一个办法
In another age, at this very spot,
多少年前 也就在这里
the first Brethren Court captured the sea goddess
第一欢海盗大会抓到了海神
and bound her in her bones.
并且因森了她
That was a mistake.
那是一个错误
We tamed the seas for ourselves.
为了我们自己 我们使大海风平浪静
But opened the door to Beckett and his ilk.
但同时也为贝克特之流 打开了方便之门
Better were the days when mastery of seas
还是那时候风光无限 那时候我们对海洋的控制
came not from bargains struck with eldritch creatures,
靠的不是与那些可怕的家伙 签订的什么契约
but from the sweat of a man's brow and the strength of his back alone.
靠的是脸上的汗水 和我们背后的背梁
You all know this to be true.
你们都知道这是真的
Gentlemen.
先生们
Ladies.
女士们
We must free Calypso.
我们必须要释放卡吕善索
- Shoot him. - Cut out his tongue!
枪毓他 割了他的得头!
Shoot him, cut out his tongue, shoot his tongue. Trim that scraggly beard.
枪毙他 割了他的舌头 拔了他的胡子
Sao Feng would have agreed with Barbossa.
趾凤会同意巴博萨的
Calypso was our enemy then, she will be now.
卡吕善索那时候是我们的笋人 现在还会是我们的数人
It's unlikely her mood's improved.
她的品性是不会改变的
I would still agree with Sao Feng. We release Calypso.
我还是同意吐风 释放卡吕普索
- You threaten me? - [challenge you.
你想威胁我 ? 我想让你闭嘴
- This is madness. - This is politics.
这简直疯了 这就是政治
Meanwhile our enemies bear down upon us.
而此时 我们的数人 正兵临城下
If they not be here already.
也许他们已经到了
You come for me.
你来找我了
You were expecting me.
你一直在等着我 ?
It has been torture.
太痛苦了
Trapped in this... single form.
因某在这个唯一的形态里
Cut off from the sea.
与大海隔绝
From all that I love.
与我所爱的一切隔绝
From you.
与你隔绝
Ten years I devoted to the duty you charged me.
十年了 我一直恪尽职守 履行着你交给我的任务
Ten years...
十年了
..l looked after those who died at sea.
我照看着 在大海中死去的人
And finally, when we could be together again...
最后当我们终于可以 在一起的时候…
.- you weren't there.
…你却没有去
Why weren't you there?
你为什么没有去 ?
Is my nature.
这是我的本性
Would you love me if was anything but what l am?
如果我不是这个样子 你还会爱我吗 ?
I do not love you.
我不爱你
Many things you were, Davy Jones.
戴维. 琼斯 你有很多的性格
But never cruel.
但你绝不残忍
You have corrupted your purpose...
你已经堕落 迷失了方向…
..and so yourself.
…连同你自己
Calypso.
卡吕普索
I will be free.
我要自由了
And when I am, I will give you my heart.
当我获得自由的时候 我会把心交给你
And we will be together always.
我们就可以永远在一起
If only you had a heart to give.
只要你还有心
Why did you come?
你为什么要来 ?
And what fate have you planned for your captors?
你想怎么处置那些 因森你的人?
The Brethren Court?
海盗大会?
All of them...
我要证…
. the last thing they will learn in this life...
他们知道…
.. 1S how cruel I can be.
…我有多么的残酷
And what of your fate, Davy Jones?
你的命运呢 戴维. 琼斯?
My heart will always belong to you.
我的心永远属于你
It was the first court what imprisoned Calypso.
是第一炊大会因禁了卡吕普索
We should be the ones to set her free.
我们应该释放她
And in her gratitude she will see fit to grant us boons.
为了表示感谢 她会报答我们的
Whose boons? Your boons?
报答谁 ? 报答你 ?
Utterly deceptive twaddle-speak, says I.
我说 这绝对是胡说八道
If you have a better alternative,
如果你有什么更好的选择
please, share.
请说出来
Cuttlefish.
乌贼
Let us not, dear friends,
我们不能 亲爱的朋友们
forget our dear friends the cuttlefish.
忘记我们亲爱的朋友 和乌赋
Flipping glorious little sausages.
挥舞着软香肠般的触角
Penned together they devour each other without a second thought.
把触角拢在一起 毫不犹移地春吃同类
Human nature, isn't it? Or fish nature.
人的本性 是吗? 或者说是鱼的本性
Yes, we could hole up here well provisioned and well armed
我们可以隐藏在这里 依靠充足的给养和精良的装备
and half of us would be dead within the month.
一个月之内就会有一半人死去
Which seems quite grim to me, any way you slice it. Or...
这一点对我来说太残酷 无论从哪方面考虑 不过…
..as my learned colleague
我那个博学的同估
so naively suggests, we can release Calypso...
提出一个天真的建议
..and we can pray that she will be merciful.
我们放了卡吕普索 祈祷她能以慈斐为怀
l rather doubt it.
我对此表示怀疑
Can we in fact pretend she is anything other than a woman scorned
我们能假装她不是个既妇
like which fury hell hath no?
她不会发港怒火?
We cannot.
我们不能
We are left with but one option.
我们只能有一个选择
l agree with, and I cannot believe the words are coming out of me mouth...
真不敢相信 我会说出这个词…
. Captain Swann.
…斯旺船长
We must fight.
我们必须战斗
- You've always run away from a fight. - Have not.
你总是逃离战场 我没有
- You have so. Have so. - Have not. Have not!
你有 你有 没有 没有 !
- Have so, and you know it. - Have not. Slander and calumny.
你有 你很清楚 没有 这是诽谤和中伤
l have only ever embraced that oldest and noblest of pirate traditions.
我信奉十老高贵的海盗传统
l submit that here now that is what we all must do.
我把它陈述给大家 这就是我们必须要做的
We must fight... to run away.
为了逃跑… …我们必须战斗
Aye!
对1!
As per the Code,
根据海盗法典
an act of war... and this be exactly that...
要发动战争 而这一炊就是战争
can only be declared by the pirate king.
只有海盗之王才有权宣战
- You made that up. - Did l now?
你里编乱造 我连编了吗 ?
I call on Captain Teague.
有请蒂格船长
Keeper of the Code.
请法典的监管人解释一下
Sri Sumbhajee proclaims this all to be folly!
印度洋海盗王宣布 这全都是荒唐的 !
Hang the code. Who gives a...
该死的法典 谁在手…
Code is the law.
法典就是法律
You're in my way, boy.
你挡着我的路了 孩子
As set forth by Morgan and Bartholomew.
就像摩根和巴塞洛旨说的
That can't... How did...?
这怎么可能…怎么…
Sea turtles, mate.
海龟 伙计
Sea turtles.
海色
Barbossa is right.
巴博萨说得没错
Hang on a minute.
稍等一下
"It shall be the duties as the king to declare war,
“海盗之王的责任包括
parley with shared adversaries..."
对外宣战 与共同的数人谈判…”
Fancy that.
想象一下
There has not been a king since the first court.
从第一炊海盗大会到现在 我们根本就没有海盗王
That's not likely to change.
看来以后也不会有
- Not likely. - Why not?
看来不会 为什么不会 ?
The pirate king is elected by popular vote.
因为海盗王是由大家
Each pirate only ever votes for hisself.
每个海盗只会投自己一标
I call for a vote.
我要求投票
I vote for Amand the Corsair.
我选伊斯兰海盗阿曼德
Capitaine Chevalle, the penniless Frenchman.
法国海盗切瓦拉船长
Sri Sumbhajee votes for Sri Sumbhajee.
印度洋海盗 印度教士
Mistress Ching.
清夫人
Gentleman Jocard.
大西洋海盗 乔卡德绅士
Elizabeth Swann.
伊丽莎白:斯旺
- Barbossa. - Villanueva!
巴博萨 瓦林纽瓦!
Elizabeth Swann.
伊丽莎白:斯旺
- What? - 1 know. Curious, isn't it?
什么 ? 我知道 很惊讶 是吧?
No!
不 你们在说什么 ?
Am I to understand that you lot will not be keeping to the Code?
我是不是可以认为你们不打算 遵守法典了?
Very well.
好吧
What say you, Captain Swann, King of the Brethren Court?
说说你想怎么干 海盗王斯旺船长 ?
Prepare every vessel that floats.
将所有的船准备好
At dawn...
在天亮之前…
..we're at war.
…我们准备迎战
And so...
这么说…
..we shall go to war.
…我们要打仗了
What?
什么 ?
You've seen it all, done it all. You survived.
你目睹了一切 参与了一切 你活了下来
That's the trick, isn't it?
这是骗人的把戏 不是吗?
To survive?
为了活下去?
It's not just about living forever, Jackie.
不仅仅是永远活下去 小杰克
The trick is living with yourself forever.
估键是要永远保住你的尊严
The enemy is here! Let's take them!
笋人来了 ! 消灭他们!
Abandon ship.
弃船 弃船
Parley?
谈判 ?
You be the cur that led these wolves to our door.
你就是那个引狼入室的秦种
Don't blame Turner. He was merely the tool of your betrayal.
不要责怪特纳 他只是你们背叛者的工具
If you wish to see its grand architect, look to your left.
如果你们想看看始作俑者 往你的左边看
My hands are clean in this.
不估我的事
Figuratively.
这是比喻
My actions were my own and to my own purpose.
一人做事一人雪 我是为了我自己的目的
- Jack had nothing to do with it. - Well spoke. Listen to the tool.
杰克与此事无多 说得好 听那个工具说的
l understand the burden you bear, but I fear that cause is lost.
我明白你身上的压力 但恐怕这条路得放弃
No cause is lost if there is but one fool left to fight for it.
这条路不会放弃 只要有一个傻瓜在为此战斗
If Turner wasn't acting on your behalf, then how did he come to give me this?
如果说特纳不代表你 那为什么他会把这个交给我 ?
You made a deal with me, Jack, to deliver the pirates. And here they are.
你和我有一笔交易 杰克 把海盗给我 而他们就在此地
Don't be bashful. Step up. Claim your reward.
别不好意思 站出来吧 说你想要什么报酬?
Your debt to me is still to be satisfied.
你久我的债还没有算清呢
One hundred years in servitude aboard the Dutchman. As a start.
作为新手 在“鬼船”上做100年苦役
That debt was paid. With some help.
那笔债已经结清了 人饮计 在某人的帮助下
You escaped.
可你逃跑了
- Technically... - l propose an exchange.
技术上是这样… 我提议进行交换
Will leaves with us...
威尔跟我们离开…
..and you can take Jack.
…-你们可以把杰克带走
Done.
同意
- Undone. - Done.
不同意
Jack's one of the nine pirate lords. You have no right.
杰克 是9名海盗首领之一 你没有权利
King.
我是海盗王
As you command, your nibs.
遵命 陆下
Blackguard!
流谍
If you have something to say, I might be saying something as well.
如果你想说什么的话 那我也有话要说
First to the finish, then?
抢占先机 是吗?
Do you fear death?
你怕死吗 ?
You've no idea.
不告诉你
Advise your brethren.
告诉你的海盗们
You can fight and all of you will die,
你们可以反抗 但结果是 全部灭亡
or you can not fight,
或者你们放弃抵抗
in which case only most of you will die.
那样的话只有一大部分人会死
You murdered my father.
你杀害了我的父亲
He chose his own fate.
是他选择了自己的命运
And you have chosen yours.
你也选择了你的
We will fight...
我们将战斗到底
..and you will die.
死的将是你
So be it.
那好吧
King?
海盗于 ?
Of the Brethren Court. Courtesy of Jack.
海盗大会选出来的 在杰克的帮助下
Maybe he really does know what he's doing.
也许他真的有什么计划
Bravo!
好啊 !
You've successfully arrived aboard the Flying Dutchman
你终于成功地有登上了“鬼船”
as per the overall scheme.
正如你计划的那样
- Look... - Oh, yes. Chapeau.
看 是的 帽子 伙计
Except for this sojourn in the brig, it's utter clockwork.
除掉被关在牢房里之外 一切都在按计划进行
Go away.
走开
- What? Back to the Locker? - Not without you, Jackie.
怎么 回疝王殿去 ? 没有你我们不去 杰克
Stab the heart.
去刺那颗心
We'll use the Black Pearl as a flagship to lead the attack.
我们要用“黑珍珠”
- Will we, now? - All right, Mrs. Fish.
哦 我们现在就放 ? 好吧 鱼太太
- Come on. - Barbossa, you can't release her.
来吧 巴博萨 不能放了她
We need to give Jack a chance.
我们需要给杰克机会
Apologies, Your Majesty.
抱娄了 陛下
Too long my fate has not been in me own hands.
我的命运总是掌握在别人手里
No longer.
现在不了
The enemy...
数人…-
..has opted for oblivion.
…选择了死亡
Ready the fleet.
舰队做好准备
To your stations!
各就各位
Be there some manner of rite or incantation?
需要举行什么仪式 或念什么咒语吗 ?
Aye.
是的
The items brought together, done.
东西已经备齐
Items to be burned.
信物将被焚烧…
And someone must speak the words,
…有人必须要说
"Calypso, I release you from your human bonds."
“卡吕普索 我要把你从 人类的东缚中释放出来
Is that it?
就这么简单 ?
'Tis said it must be spoken as if to a lover.
听说应该像对恋人说话那样
Calypso, I release you from your human bonds!
卡吕普索 我要把你从 人类的束缚中灵放出来
Is that it?
是这样吗 ?
He didn't say it right.
不 他没说对
You have to say it right.
你必须说对了才行
Calypso...
卡吕普索…
..[ release you from your human bonds.
…我要把你从 人类的束缚中灵放出来
Tia Dalma.
蒂亚.达尔玛
Calypso.
卡吕普索
When the Brethren Court imprisoned you, who was it that told them how?
海盗大会因禁你时 是谁告诉他们囚禁你的方法?
Who was it that betrayed you?
是谁藻叛了你 ?
Name him.
是谁?
Davy Jones.
戴维.， 琼斯
This is it!
成功了 !
Calypso...
卡吕普索 !
..1 come before you as but a servant...
作为你的仆人我谦卑必悔地
.. humble and contrite.
来到你的面前
I have fulfilled me vow
我已经实践了我的诺言
and now ask your favor.
我现在请求你大慈大悲
Spare meself, me ship, me crew...
宽恕我 我的船 我的水手…
..but unleash your fury upon those who dare pretend themselves your masters...
…把你的怒火释放给 那些胆敢冒充你我主字
. ..or mine.
的胆大亡为之人
Is that it?
就这些吗 ?
Why, she's no help at all.
怎么 她一点用都没有
What now?
现在怎么办?
Nothing.
不怎么办
Our final hope has failed us.
我们最后的努力失败了
- It's not over. - There's still a fight to be had.
还没有结束 我们还要进行一场战斗
We've an armada against us
面对一个舰队
and with the Dutchman there's no chance.
再加上“匈船” 我们没有机会
There's only a fool's chance.
还有一线渺茫的希望
Revenge won't bring your father back, Miss Swann,
报优并不能使你的父亲复活 斯旺小姐
and it's not something I'm intending to die for.
也不值得我为此而死
You're right.
你说得对
Then what shall we die for?
那我们为什么而死呢?
You will listen to me.
你们听我说
Listen!
听着 !
The Brethren will still be looking here to us...
别的船都在看着我们…
..to the Black Pear! to lead.
…看着我们的“黑珍珠号”
And what will they see?
他们会看到什么呢?
Frightened bilge rats aboard a derelict ship? No.
船上的一群胆小鬼 ? 不
No, they will see free men...
不 他们会看到自由的人
..and freedom!
会看到自由1!
What the enemy will see is the flash of our cannons.
我们的数人会看到 我们炮口中喷射出的火光
They will hear the ring of our swords, and they will know what we can do...
会听到我们的刀剑发出的声响 他们会知道我们的能力
..by the sweat of our brows...
用我们脸上的汗水
..the strength of our backs...
和我们背后的背梁…
..and the courage of our hearts.
…用我们心中的勇气
Gentlemen...
先生们…-
.-hoist the colors.
…升起船旗
Hoist the colors.
升起船旗
- Hoist the colors. - Hoist the colors!
升起船旗 !
Aye.
是的
The wind's on our side, boys.
风站在我们这边 弟兄们
That's all we need!
这就足够了
Hoist the colors!
升起船旗 !
We have a favorable wind, sir.
风向对我们有利 勋着
Oh, so we do.
哦 是这样
Signal Jones to give no quarter.
告诉戴维. 琼斯不要怜巾
That should brighten his day.
大开杀戒会令他开心的
To arms! We give no quarter!
准备好武器 我们决不怜巾 !
Calypso.
卡吕普索
Have you noticed on top of everything it's raining?
你看到了吗 老天居然下起了本 ?
That's a bad sign.
这是不祥之兆
Man the capstan. Ready the main topyard.
转动绞盘 升起主栅
Keep that powder dry.
别弄湿弹药
Maelstrom!
大洲洱 !
Captain Barbossa!
巴博萨船长 !
We need you at the helm.
我们需要你来掌舵
Aye, that be true.
是的 没错
Brace up yards, you cack-handed deck apes.
国定住船梅 你们这些策蛋
Dying is the day worth living for.
死也要死得其所
Veer off!
改变航向 !
She'll not harm us.
她不会把我们怎么样
Full bore and into the abyss.
全速进入旋涡
Are you mad?
你鸳了吗 ?
You afraid to get wet?
你害怕把身上青湿 ?
She's on our stern and gaining.
她在我们的船尾 在加速
More speed!
加速 !
Haul your wind and hold your water.
利用你的凤 利用你的水
Bow cannons!
船首炮准备 !
Take us out, or they'll overbear us.
快点出去 不然会被他们干掉
Nay. Further in.
不 继续前进
We'll cut across to faster waters.
我们抄近路进入急流
Prepare to broadside.
船航炮准备
Captain the guns. Bear a hand.
指挥大炮 增派人手
Muster your courage, men. At the ready.
鼓起你们的勇气 饮计们 准备射击
Fill the cannons.
加炸弹
- Hinges. Hinges. Hinges. - Think like the whelp.
贸链 锐链
Half-barrel hinges.
破破烂烂的匀链
Leverage.
拉
Wish us luck, boys. We'll need it.
祝我们好运吧 我们需要它
- [miss him already. - He is quite charming, isn't he?
我已经开始想他了 他很可爱 对吧 ?
Nobody move.
都不要动
dropped me brain.
我的脑子寺了
Batten down the hatches!
压住般门!
Stand to your guns.
坚守炮位
Midship cannoneers sight the mast.
中部炮位 晓准横杆
Main battery at the ready.
主炮群准备射击 !
Hold there.
准备好
Wait till we're board-and-board.
等待最佳时机再开火
Fire!
开火 !
Fire! Fire all!
开火 !开火!
Come on, men.
快 伙计们
It be too late to alter course now, mateys.
现在改变航向太晚了 伙计
Halt there, or we'll shoot.
站住 不然我们开枪了
Good one.
射得好
I just come to get me effects.
我到此只是来取我的东西
Admirable though it may be,
这国然令人钦佩 可你们
why are you here when you could be elsewhere?
为什么非要采在这个地方 ?
Someone has to stay and guard the chest.
得有人守卫这个箱子
There's no question,
没错 在这条船上
there has been a breakdown in military discipline on this vessel.
有人违反了军纪
- [blame the fish people. - Oh, so fish people,
都怪那些鱼人 哦 这么说鱼人
by dint of being fish people,
凭借和鱼人的身份
automatically aren't as disciplined as non-fish people?
自然而然就不用 像非鱼人一样遵守军纪?
Seems contributory, I'm suggesting.
我的意思是说 看起来是这样
Well, if there were no fish people, there'd be no need to guard the chest.
的确 假如没有鱼人 就没有必要守卫这只箱子
And if there were no chest, we wouldn't need to guard it.
如果没有这只箱子 我们就没必要在这里把守
Prepare to board!
准备和登船 !
Cover!
掩扩 !
Lookie here, boys.
看啊 孩子们
A lost bird.
一只落单的小鸟
A lost bird that never learned to fly.
落单的小岛永远也学不会飞
To my great regret.
我非常遗碱
But...
不过…-
...never too late to learn, eh?
…想学会飞什么时候都不晚
The chest, hand it over.
把箱子给我
I can set you free, mate.
我可以让你获得自由 伙计
My freedom was forfeit long ago.
我的自由早就没有了
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
..Will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗 ?
I don't think now's the best time.
我不觉得现在是最好的时候
Now may be the only time.
不然可能就来不及了
I love you.
我爱你
I've made my choice. What's yours?
我已经决定了 你呢?
Barbossa.
巴博萨
Marry us.
来给我们证婚吧
I'm a little busy at the moment.
我现在有点忙
Barbossa, now.
巴博萨 快点几
Fine then.
那好吧
Dearly beloved, we be gathered here today.
亲爱的来宾 我们今天欢聚在这里…
To nail your gizzards to the mast, you poxy cur.
我把你钉在术杆上 你这个杂种
Elizabeth Swann, do you take me to be your husband?
伊丽莎白:斯旺 愿意接受我成为你的丈夫吗 ?
- ldo. - Great.
太好了
..to be your wife?
…成为你的和要子…
In sickness and in health.
无论她生病还是健康…
Health being the less likely.
…很有可能不健康 你愿意吗 ?
Ido.
我愿意
As captain, l now pronounce you...
作为船长 我现在宣布…
You may kiss...
你们可以亲吻了
Just kiss.
亲吧
Leave it.
放下
You can do nothing without the key.
没有钥是你什么也干不了
l already have the key.
我有钥是
No, you don't.
不 你没有
Oh, that key.
哦 那把钥是
No.
不 !
My pistol.
哦 我的手枪
Turner.
特纳
Fire.
开火 !
Thank you, Jack.
谢谢你 杰克
It's me.
住手 ! 是我 !
Your son.
你的儿子
Go.
走!
Harridan! You'll see no mercy from me.
泼妇 ! 我贷不了你
That's why I brought this.
所以我拿着这个
I'm not going to kill you. I made you a promise.
我不杀你 我发过考
Mister...
没扎中
..did you forget?
你忘了吗 ?
I'm a heartless wretch.
我没有心
A dreadful bond.
可怕的束缚
And yet...
这么…
..S0 easily severed.
…容易就得到满足
Tell me, William Turner, do you fear death?
告诉我 威廉. 特纳 你怕死吗 ?
Do you?
你呢 ?
Heady tonic, holding life and death in the palm of one's hands.
真让人兴奋 手握生杀大权
You're a cruel man, Jack Sparrow.
你这个残酷的杰克 斯派罗
Cruel is a matter of perspective.
残酷看清事物本质
Is it?
是吗?
Will.
威尔?
Look at me! Stay with me! You're all right.
看着我 ! 不要离开我 ! 你没事的 !
William?
威廉?
My son.
我的儿子
Will! Look at me. Look at me!
威尔?感尔? 看着我 看着我 !
You will not forestall my judgment.
你不能阻止我
Calypso.
卡吕普索
She's taking us down.
我们快被吞没了 !
Make quick or it's the Locker for us all.
快点 不然我们就要见交王了
No. No. No!
不不不不!
Part of the ship, part of the crew.
水手中的一员 与船不可分害
Don't leave me.
不要离开我
I won't leave you.
我不会离开你
The Dutchman must have a captain.
“鬼船”不能没有船长
Hold on.
抓住了
Thank goodness, Jack.
感谢上帝 杰克
The armada is still out there. Endeavor's coming up hard to starboard
笋人的舰队还在外面 右航吃紧
and I think it's time we embrace that oldest and noblest of pirate traditions.
我想我们现在应该遵守 二老高贵的海盗传统
I've never actually been one for tradition.
我从来不是什么守盏的人
Close haul her. Luff the sails and lay her in irons.
顶风接近 抢凤行驶 包围她
- Belay that. We'll be a sitting duck. - Belay that "belay that."
不能那样 香则我们就成了挨打的目标
- Captain... If we... - Belay. Stow. Shut it.
但是笋舰…… 别说了 行了 闭嘴
What are they waiting for?
他们在等什么 ?
He expects us to honor our agreement.
他希望我们能遵守约定
It's nothing personal, Jack. It's just good business.
这不是个人思丐 杰克 这是一宗好买卖
She survived.
啊 她又复活了
Ready on the guns.
把武器准备好 准备好武咒
Full canvas.
升满帆
Aye, full canvas.
是 升满凯
Orders, sir.
下令呀 勋芷
Sir!
勋病 !
Captain.
船长
- Fire. - Fire!
开火 开火 !
Orders? Orders, sir?
下令呀 下令呀 勋责?
What do you command?
勋圳 请下命令
..good business.
…好买卖
Abandon ship!
弃船 !
All hands, abandon ship!
全体 弃船 !
They're turning away.
他们掉头跑了 !
Wind in your sails.
祝你们一路顺风
Shiver me timbers.
真见鬼
- Mr. Gibbs. - Captain?
吉布斯先生 船长?
- You may throw my hat if you like. - Aye, aye, Captain.
你可以扔我的蝎子 是 船长
Hooray!
万岁 !
Now go and get it.
现在去给我捡回来
Orders, sir?
有命令吗 长官?
You're no longer bound to the Dutchman.
你不再是“鬼船”的因徒
- You're free. - Aye.
你自由了 器 匹
That's a fine thing, but...
这国然不错 不过…-
..by my reckoning, I still have a debt that has to be paid.
…我觉得 我还有一笔债没还
If you'll have me.
如果你能让我留下
On the wheel then, Mr. Turner.
那你就去掌舵吧 特纳先生
Aye, Captain Turner.
是 特纳船长
This ship has a purpose again.
这条船又一灵有了使命
And where we are bound, she cannot come.
而我们要去的地方… …她无法前往
One day ashore.
岸上一天
Ten years at sea.
海上十年
It's a steep price for what's been done.
这是一个巨大的代价
Depends on the one day.
这就要取决于那一天了
Your chariot awaits, your highness.
您的战车已经备好 殿下
The oars are inside.
船桨在里面
Mrs. Turner.
特纳夫人
Good-bye, poppet.
再见 乖孩子
It would never have worked out between us.
我们之间不会有什么结果
Keep telling yourself that, darling.
你还是对自己说吧 亲爱的
Once is quite enough.
一灾就够了
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm going to need the other one.
我还需要另外那一只
It's nearly sunset.
太阳快落了
It's always belonged to you.
它永远属于你
Will you keep it safe?
你会保管好吗 ?
Yes.
是的
Will!
威尔 !
Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
睁大眼睛 看着地平线
Granted it tends to list to port
同意它停靠港口
and has been, on occasion, known to frighten young women.
有的时候会吓着年轻的女人
But I promise you,
不过我向你们保证
you will not be disappointed.
你们不会失望的
Is that it?
就是它?
The Black Pearl?
“黑珍珠号”?
It's not very big.
这么小?
Love, that is a dinghy.
亲爱的 那只是条小徐
My vessel is magnificent and fierce and huge-ish
我的船壮观 威猛 巨大…
and... gone.
…可是不见了
Why is it gone?
它去哪儿了?
Is that it there?
是那里的那条船吗 ?
Why is it there?
怎么跑到那儿去了 ?
- It's much larger up close. - You promised to take us for a ride.
走近了可大了 你答应过我们让我们坐船
Il was to be given the first ride.
你答应让我第一个上船
What? You?
什么?你?
- Not what he said. - [ never!
他没这么说 我不会 !
Mr. Gibbs?
吉布斯先生 ?
Any particular reason why my ship is gone?
是什么原因 导致我的船不见了?
The ship? We're on the ship.
船?我们就在船上
Jack!
杰克 !
- The ship's gone! - Really?
船不见了 ! 真的?
Ladies! Will you please shut it?
女士们 ! 你们能不能给我闭嘴 ?
Listen to me.
听我说
Yes, I lied to you. No, I don't love you.
是的 我欺骗了你们 不 我不爱你
Of course it makes you look fat. I've never been to Brussels.
你这样确实显得很胖 我没去过布鲁塞尔
It is pronounced "egregious."
它的发音是“伊蕊理基尔斯”
By the way, no, I've never actually met Pizarro, but I love his pies.
另外我也没见过皮萨罗 不过我很喜欢他的财富
All this pales to utter insignificance
但现在说什么也没用了
in light of the fact that my ship is once again gone. Savvy?
我的船又一交让人开跑了 明白了吗?
- Take what you can. - Give nothing back.
拿上能拿的东西 什么也不用还
Tell me, ladies...
告诉我 女士们
.. what do you know of sea turtles?
你们对海龟了解多少?
- Sea turtles? - Let me tell you young ladies...
海色? 让我来告诉你们
You want this?
哦 你想尝尝这个?
That's a good boy! You're Daddy's boy. Yes, you are.
哦 真是个好孩子 ! 和爸和爸的好孩子
- Yes, you are. - Sir?
哦 是的 没错 先生
Some of the men don't feel entirely settled
我们有些人心里觉得过意不去
about leaving Captain Jack behind.
把杰克一个人甩下
- Again.
再一次甩下 再一次
Is that so?
是这样吗 ?
It would make us feel a whole lot better regarding our fortunes
如果我们能看到那个 跟我们的财富有僚的东西
if we could see that item you told us about.
我们会感党好受一些
On the charts.
在海图上
- Aye. - With our own eyes.
器 匹 我们想亲眼看一看
To help put an ease to our burden of guilt, so to speak.
以减轻我们心中的内疫
Feast your eyes upon this, mateys.
那就让你们饱饱了眼福吧
There's more than one way to live forever.
想得到永生 不正一条路可走
Gents, I give you the Fountain of Youth.
先生们 我要向你们展示 “青春之泉”
Sparrow.
斯派罗
We're devils and black sheep Really bad eggs
我们是魔鬼 是败类 是真正的坏蛋
Drink up me hearties Yo ho
干杯 我的伙伴 哟吐
Yo ho, yo ho A pirate’s life for me
哟轨 哟吐 我要过海盗生活
We pillage, we plunder We rifle and loot
我们掠夺 我们抢劫
Drink up me hearties Yo ho
干杯 我的伙伴 哟吐
We kidnap and ravage and don't give a hoot
我们绑架 我们复仇 我们不在卑
Drink up me hearties Yo ho
干杯 我的伙伴 哟吐
Yo ho, yo ho
哟轨 哟吐
A pirate’s life for me
我要过海盗生活